#### **MARY DUSABE**

PO BOX 62000-00200

Nairobi, Kenya

dusabemary9@gmail.com

+254799461490

### **PERSONAL DETAILS**

Nationality: Kenyan.

ID No:36806715.

Date of Birth:3rd September1999.

Marital status: Single.

Gender: Female.

Religion: Christian.

Languages: English and Swahili

#### **CAREER OBJECTIVES**

I'm driven by the fear of being average and therefore I'm looking for an opportunity to further my skills and knowledge by key participation in team oriented tasks and immediate challenges that will propel me into being competent in my field of study.

My long term goal is gaining as much knowledge as possible in the field of Instrumentation and Control and as a result have the ability to offer engineering solutions.

#### **PERSONAL PROFILE**

I'm a highly principled and ambitious individual, I embrace team oriented tasks but also works

equally best in individual tasks. I am highly adaptive to new environments and able to work well under no or minimal supervision. My interest in research and analysis has made me automatically develop good writing skills.

### ACADEMIC BACKGROUND

2017 - 2021: Bachelor of Science in Control and Instrumentation – Jomo Kenyatta University

• Research Project: Investigating the performance of ionospheric models in estimating position for IGS sites in Kenya using gLAB

Jan – May 2017 – Information Technology stage 1- St. Bakhita Training Institute

2013 – 2016: Kenya certificate of Secondary Education- Uthiru Girls' High School

2005 – 2012 Kenya Certificate of Primary Education – Ruai Primary School.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

2017-2021- Online tutoring services Mathematics and Physics.

• My duties included: Creating written and video solutions to questions asked by students.

2019-Attachment at Kenya Power and Lighting Company.

 Participated in the following tasks: System control and protection, Power Substations technical service, Overhead Electrical line maintenance, Design and construction of power transmissions systems

2018-2019- Private High school tutoring Mathematics and Physics

• My duties included: Teaching mathematics and physics, creating exams and solutions.

### PERSONAL SKILLS

Good written and oral communication

Problem solving

Good team player and Organization skills

Good interpersonal skills

# **PROFESSIONAL SKILLS**

Computer programming using C++ and Matlab

Electronic simulations using different softwares such as Proteus and Multism

Z80 microprocessor, Arduino and PLC Programming

Reading and interpreting wiring diagrams

Good editing skills using Microsoft office and LATEX

# **ACTIVITIES AND INTERESTS**

Scientific Research

Member and participant of technovation community work

High school ministry; involved in bible-based motivational speaking

Evangelism/Mission Work to the unreached societies in Kenya

Playing volleyball and basketball

Volunteering experience for social, academic and religious work.

## **LEADERSHIP EXPERIENCE**

Youth's Minister- Full Gospel Church 2019 to date.

Treasurer – NET Ministries Trust JKUAT Unit 2019/2021

Ushering Head and treasurer- JKUAT CU 2018-2020

Science and Engineering projects and innovation Chairperson- Uthiru Girls High School 2015-

2016

Laboratory Head- Uthiru Girls High School 2014-2016

## **HONOURS AND ACHIEVEMENTS**

Achieved grade A in all 14 units in 2018/2019 academic year equivalent to GPS 4.0

Received an award for volunteer work as a Teens minister

Received an award for achieving 3<sup>rd</sup> position in national mathematics contest at Alliance High School in 2016

Maintained a GPA of 3.7 and above for all the 4 years of university

Participated and completed short course on chronological bible teaching and training.

# **REFEREES**

1. Dr. Calvin Ominde.

Senior Lecturer

JKUAT Physics Dept.

+254 720662605

ominde@fsc.jkuat.ac.ke

2. Angela Kamau.

Operations and Maintenance Engineer.

Kenya Power and lighting Company.

+254 727 892510

angelakamau@kplc.co.ke

3. Dr. Anthony Kiroe

Chairman

JKUAT Physics Department.

+25427756508

kiroe@fsc.jkuat.ac.ke